<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog.cowger.us</title>
    <link>https://blog.cowger.us/</link>
    <description>Recent content on blog.cowger.us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 13:56:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cowger.us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun Stuff in Tokyo</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-11-06-fun-stuff-in-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 13:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-11-06-fun-stuff-in-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>I recently went to Tokyo to present at a Dell EMC Forum and deliver a cloud native training class (which is open source - check it out). I had a truly awesome time, and want to share some of the spots I loved and tips I learned.
 We had a truly incredible experience at a sake bar called Ganko Oyaji on the edge of the Shinjuku and Shibuya districts. Its maybe a 5 minute walk from Shinjuku station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Agile, DevOps and Containers</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-11-02-getting-started-with-agile-devops-and-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 15:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-11-02-getting-started-with-agile-devops-and-containers/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of requests lately from friends and colleagues on how to get started with these ideas, and what they can read. I recently rewrote that email for like the 10th time, so here it is in blog post form:
I think you need to be able to come from where your customers come from…and that means I think you need to learn to write code….the primary challenges in the DevOps and cloud native world are around deploying, managing and maintaining code, and there’s no way to really understand whats happening with platforms, containers, CI/CD, DevOps without understanding the basics of the code pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiring in Boston</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-08-08-hiring-in-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 11:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-08-08-hiring-in-boston/</guid>
      <description>Want to work for the most fun team in Dell EMC?
Of course you do :).
In case you hadn’t heard, the Field Evangelism team I run here at Dell is pretty awesome. We’ve got seriously fun, smart people like Sam Maracinni, Tommy Trogden, Luke Mahon, Fabio Chiodini, Dionne Ane and Dragana Beara already spreading the message and having fun doing it. I need someone in the Boston area to round this out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Factors in the Real World</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2016-08-19-12-factors-in-the-real-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 15:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2016-08-19-12-factors-in-the-real-world/</guid>
      <description>For those of you that don&amp;rsquo;t know, Reddit is a pretty major site on the internet. They bill themselves as the &amp;lsquo;front page of the Internet&amp;rsquo;, and they are#25 for traffic globally. They are based in San Francisco and have about 80 employees, the majority of which focus just on keeping the site alive and performing well.
Think about that for a moment - they have a single site, and at least 40 employees dedicated to making it work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Team for a New Application</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2016-01-14-a-new-team-for-a-new-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2016-01-14-a-new-team-for-a-new-application/</guid>
      <description>I posted earlier this year that I was changing roles - just within the first couple weeks its been a whirlwind internally letting people know, meeting with EMC leadership, getting silly technical issues fixed so I report the right way internally, etc. But its also been fun - this is a brand new team, and with my colleagues, we get to shape it from the start.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick description.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2016-12-28-the-community-quad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2016-12-28-the-community-quad/</guid>
      <description>The VMworld Community Quad Community is such a strong force in technology, and yet often underestimated. There are dozens of project and tools out there that are successful because of their communities (sometimes in spite of their technical quality ahem PHP, Drupal, etc), and some die on the vine because of a failure to nuture community. I dont have anyway to back this up, but I suspect that the there are times that community managers keep a project alive because of their efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cloud Foundry Story - Idea to Production in 90 Minutes</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-09-04-a-cf-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-09-04-a-cf-story/</guid>
      <description>A Cloud Foundry Story - Idea to Production in 90 Minutes
One of the best parts of what I do is making demos - they are an awesome combination of playing with the latest technology, making it do something cool (but understandable) and not having to support it for more than a couple months.
This year, for EMCworld and VMworld, I wrote a demo called &amp;lsquo;Vasco da Gama&amp;rsquo; that was used in a number of places, including Chad&amp;rsquo;s blog, his session at VMworld and at the EMC booth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Stablemate</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-03-23-new-stablemate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-03-23-new-stablemate/</guid>
      <description>Last week I noted that I had come to the end of the 3 year lease of my Ford Focus Electric - my first electric car. At the time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t indicate what replaced it, which is what this post will cover.
Requirements: I learned a lot about my needs in the last 3 years. I used that to inform my next set of requirements.
 200+ miles range. Range anxiety on an electric car is a real thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Careful With Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-03-02-be-careful-how-you-benchmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-03-02-be-careful-how-you-benchmark/</guid>
      <description>Warning: VERY technical post ahead
I read an interesting article last night from Kenny Coleman and Clint Kitson on the merits of compiled / lower level languages, and they had some fascinating views.
First, they noted that they felt that:
 But in terms of lines of code, if you can remove some of the magic under the covers and expose more of the code in the application then you have more control and thus can ensure better predictability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a VCDX Panelist is Anti-Community</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-02-11-being-a-panelist-is-anti-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-02-11-being-a-panelist-is-anti-community/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a VCDX since around Sept 2010, when I passed a VCDX3 series of exams and defense. At that time, and today still, community is one of the most important parts (if not the most important parts) of the program. I know that if I get a request from a fellow VCDX, its probably important and worth considering in its fullest.
Thats why a recent email from the VCDX Program Manager (who runs the program afterMark Brunstad left VMware) has me very concerned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Movement - Jekyll &amp; GitHub Pages &amp; Disqus</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-01-16-blog-movements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-01-16-blog-movements/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never really liked Wordpress. Its heavyweight (heavier certainly than I need, and supports a thousand plugins I&amp;rsquo;ll never use). Its written in PHP . It requires MySQL (which no one should be using). It requires me to run my own server and do my own patching/maintenance, which I&amp;rsquo;d rather not do.
So I had been looking for an alternate platform, and a post from Scott Lowe inspired me to try the Jekyll route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Workflow with Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-02-02-blog-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-02-02-blog-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Ever since my post about moving my blog to GitHub Pages and Jekyll, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a couple requests for my &amp;lsquo;workflow&amp;rsquo;, or how I use this on a daily basis.
In my opinion, its pretty simple, and easy.
I generally start by opening my text editor to get started writing. I generally prefer to use a light weight text editor for this sort of thing (rather than a dedicated Markdown editor, for example), and I&amp;rsquo;ve found that Atom from Github is actually quite good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes - They Are Afoot</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2016-01-04-more-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2016-01-04-more-changes/</guid>
      <description>People make all sorts of predictions this time of year. Analysts do it. Media do it. Heck, even executives do it. I don&amp;rsquo;t make these kinds of posts or predictions, because honestly if I thought I could predict that well I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t publish it - I&amp;rsquo;d be investing in the market :). Instead I do the smart thing and invest in mutual funds :).
That being said, I do recognize trends, and when I see something that has wings, I tend to focus on that and follow it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CloudFoundry Abacus Inception</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-08-06-cf-abacus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-08-06-cf-abacus/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I had the privilege of attending the inception meeting for the newest incubated Cloud Foundry project - Abacus.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t looked at it, the short version is that its a service usage and metering tool for Cloud Foundry services, so we can go a bit further than the &amp;lsquo;all or nothing&amp;rsquo; method that we have today. Services can submit usage data to a CF instance, have it rated and billed as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CloudFoundry Summit Quick Take</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-05-14-cfsummit-quick-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-05-14-cfsummit-quick-take/</guid>
      <description>I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just write a quick review of the Cloud Foundry Summit I attended last week. Note: Everything was recorded and will be posted over the next couple weeks, and when that happens I will post another set of links to the best talks.
#Major Announcements: * 1400 attendees (+50% from last year). * JP Morgan Chase joins the CF Foundation * The second major financial to join * New Relic joins the federation * The first major SaaS provider I&amp;rsquo;ve seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying ScaleIO with Terraform</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-09-09-terraform-for-scaleio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-09-09-terraform-for-scaleio/</guid>
      <description>Almost 2 years ago, shortly after EMC acquired ScaleIO, I demonstrated the deployment of ScaleIO in AWS at significant scales - up to 1000 nodes. It was pretty fun and got some solid traction on Chad&amp;rsquo;s blog and at an EMCworld keynote.
Now, that was cool, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked many times for how to replicate that. While the code was open source, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t very clean, and was quite fragile, and no one but me was able to get it working&amp;hellip;and thats bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Data Breaches Impact Shareholder Value - A Quick Analysis</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-10-27-do-data-breaches-impact-shareholder-value---a-quick-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-10-27-do-data-breaches-impact-shareholder-value---a-quick-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I had an interesting chat on twitter today with a friend and colleague Wade O&amp;rsquo;Harrow. He used to be at a bunch of places, but currently leads the SE team for HyTrust, a security company (yes, thats oversimplifying it). He started the exhange with:
 Data is growing at exponential rates, and the trend of Corporate data breaches is staggering. still many question the need for protection.
 and we eventually wandered into the discussion of what data breaches cost shareholders, with Wade making the suggestion that</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End of an Era - Sort Of</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-03-20-end-of-an-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-03-20-end-of-an-era/</guid>
      <description>No - I&amp;#39;m not leaving Dell 😊.
3 years ago I bought my first fully electric car – a 2014 Ford Focus Electric. You can read about my initial impressions, but today is for my final ones, because my 3 year lease is up.
I&amp;#39;ve been quite happy with the Focus Electric, overall.
Driving Dynamics : I always trusted the car. Like the ICE Focus and the Focuses (Foci?) before it, the Ford Focus Electroc (FFE) has a pretty good, patient, predictable suspension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Hiring - Want To Come Work for the Most Fun Team @ Dell?</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-02-23-im-hiring-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2017-02-23-im-hiring-again/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Thanks for all the support and great resumes. For now we&amp;rsquo;ve closed the process and are considering the candidates we have. Once we&amp;rsquo;ve made some hires, you know where you&amp;rsquo;ll find more info!
Of course you do :). In case you hadn’t heard, the Field Evangelism team I run here at Dell is pretty awesome. We’ve got seriously fun, smart people like Sam Maracinni, Tommy Trogden, Luke Mahon, Brian Verkley &amp;amp; Fabio Chiodini already spreading the message and having fun doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to S3 and CloudFront</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2016-01-05-moving-to-s3-and-cloudfront/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2016-01-05-moving-to-s3-and-cloudfront/</guid>
      <description>Last yeah I posted about the process of converting my blog to a &amp;lsquo;static&amp;rsquo; site vs. Wordpress, and what that took.
One of the choices I made at that time was to host the site using GitHub Pages because of the ease of use. Publishing was a simple matter of git commit &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git push so its was great.
However, I did find a few things over the last year I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fan of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My EMCworld Sessions/Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-05-01-emcworld-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-05-01-emcworld-2015/</guid>
      <description>So, yet again, EMCworld is coming up, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be at the show.
##What I&amp;rsquo;m Doing
This year, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a session in which I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting, but I will be working the &amp;lsquo;App Agility&amp;rsquo; booth with Tyler Britten  and Drew Dimmick. We&amp;rsquo;ll be showing off a fully opensource application that Tyler and I wrote using all of the 12-factor principles, running on Cloud Foundry (via Pivotal Web Services) and doing live, on-dmand, no-net code changes and pushing them live to the cloud on request from customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New VNX Techbook Posted</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-01-20-new-vnx-techbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-01-20-new-vnx-techbook/</guid>
      <description>This is just a quick post in case you missed it like I did. The VNX team has just published a new version of document h8229, better known as the vSphere VNX Techbook - the bible of using VNX with vSphere.
There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of new content in there around best practices for vSphere 5.5 and VNX2. Special consideration to:
 UNMAP (p. 70) iSCSI configuration (p. 43) SSD Pools (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Armor Review</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-04-08-tech-armor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-04-08-tech-armor/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago I wrote a review of a screen protector from Zagg, that got some visibility, and was recently contacted by Tech Armor to see if I was willing to do a similar review of their new line for the iPhone 6.
disclosure, they sent me a free one to test, but do not (and did not ask to) exercise any control over this post - nor are they an advertiser, as I simply dont have any)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Out Android...Again</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-04-06-trying-out-android-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-04-06-trying-out-android-again/</guid>
      <description>The Start For the first time in 4 years, I spent a signficant and notable time using an Android device as my primary device. My last experience was with an HTC Thunderbolt 4G running HTC Sense 2, and it was terrible. Laggy, slow, dropped calls, etc. Even with third party ROMs (like Cyanogen 7 at the time) it was improved, but bad. I very quickly shelved it (I still have it, actually) and stayed with my iPhones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Conferences</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-04-08-conferences-coming-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-04-08-conferences-coming-up/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Conferences Conference season has started, and I figured it was a good time to update what I&amp;rsquo;m working on and where I&amp;rsquo;ll be.
#CF Summit
First up is the CloudFoundry Summit. If you&amp;rsquo;ve paid attention to my recent posts and tweets, you can see how supportive I am of this project. Its the only PaaS out there thats ready for production and open source and compatible with pretty much any cloud provider, and so I think its REALLY important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Air Is A Terrible AWS Alternative - And That&#39;s Good</title>
      <link>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-01-21-vcloud-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cowger.us/post/2015-01-21-vcloud-air/</guid>
      <description>It really is a terrible AWS alternative. The focus of the vCloud Air is an entirely different design center. How can you tell? Easily, through a variety of lenses. Just 2 to start with:
 Look at the technology used. The compute is standard off-the-shelf hardware, but everything is dual pathed, dual power supplied, etc. The network is all high end gear. The storage is all very high end hardware designed for resiliency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>